

O Montevideo, Uruguay

+59891853831

Profile

Although I have a broad background and knowledge in various technologies and subjects, my professional experience has primarily focused on front-end development and web stack since 2017.

I have gained valuable experience in taking ownership and responsibility during critical stages of the business cycle. As a result, I have developed the ability to translate complex product requirements into practical solutions.

My passion lies in the development of human-machine interfaces, particularly in interactive content. With over four years of experience in React, Redux, and other state management libraries, I am proficient in writing custom hooks and producing testable code for both large applications and client-facing websites. I adhere to industry best practices to ensure that the core product can be scaled and upgraded more cost-effectively and with greater accountability.

Employment History

Front End engineer, tem energy - Renewables & Environment, London (remote)

November 2022 — November 2023

This is a start-up in its early days, where I have been able to learn from talented colleagues and a successful MVP with state-of-the-art of current web technologies.

- React
- Type Script
- · Styled components
- RTK Query
- Data visualization
- Storybook
- Story Block
- Next.js
- Animations

React engineer, emmy-sharing (GO-TO global) - Electric mobility, Berlin January 2022 — July 2022

In this small, fast-growing company I was able to contribute to the code base from the beginning. Updating projects, redesigning the user interface, and building new components and business requirements by direct feedback from users.

I was also in front of the creation of wireframes and layer designs in Figma.

- React (TypeScript)
- Zustand
- Rest API
- Material UI V5

Links

Linkedin

Profile Site

Skills

React

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Type Script

MUI

Redux

web GL

GraphQL

Gatsby

Agile and Scrum

Figma

CSS

Netx.js

Languages

Spanish; Castilian

English

Italian

- Storybook
- Custom hooks
- Full responsive design
- High API data traffic
- Figma
- SCSS modules

Front End Developer, Accenture - Senior consultant, Milan

February 2021 — December 2021

During this cycle, I worked with corporate clients on large-scale projects with numerous teams under my scope of responsibility. Working to provide industry-leading solutions.

- Front-End development

- React.js
- Redux
- Customized React template for libraries and applications
- Micro front ends
- Java Script / Prop-types
 - libraries and documentation
- CSS processors and responsive design
- Test-driven development
 - Unit Testing
 - E2E Testing

- Azure DevOps & Azure pipelines

Creative Technologist / Software Developer, Human Beyond Labs, Amsterdam

April 2017 — December 2019

A creative studio that focuses on interactive storytelling through immersive installations using Al. My contribution helped to improve customer satisfaction rates.

- Al-based software development for computer vision

- Tensor Flow & Tensor Flow.js
- Neural networks for image generation
- Interactive installations/web Apps as a product demo

- Front End developer + Creative Technologist

- Node.js
- React.js
- Three.js
- Vue.js
- Nuxt.js
- Firebase

Unity Developer & Performer , OpenLab, Buenos Aires, Cordoba, Argentina December 2016 — December 2017

A hybrid piece of dance and interactive technology created alongside a team of game developers, visual artists, dancers, and musicians, which won the "Obreros del Lápiz" promotion funding by the Universidad Nacional de Córdoba (UNC)

Education

Software studies

May 2015 — Present

I am a self-taught computer science professional with a passion for web technologies. I have honed my skills through extensive self-study and have developed strong documentation and time management abilities. I am constantly seeking out new opportunities to learn and stay current in the industry, by participating in courses, attending conferences and workshops.

I have a solid understanding of the following technologies and have experience utilizing them to deliver successful projects:

Front-end Development:

- React: Strong experience in building scalable and performant web applications using React and its ecosystem (e.g. Redux, Hooks, Context API)
- Gatsby and Next.js: Experience in building fast, secure and optimized websites with these frameworks.
- JavaScript/Typescript: Proficient in building complex applications using these languages, familiar with the latest features and best practices.
- HTML5, CSS animations: Experience in creating responsive, accessible and visually engaging web pages.
- Three.js, Green Sock: Experience in creating 3D animations and interactive web experiences using these libraries.
- GraphQL: Experience in building GraphQL APIs and integrating with various front-end frameworks.

Back-end Development:

 Node.js: Experience in building back-end applications, APIs and web-scraping using Node.js

DevOps:

 Docker, Kubernetes: Experience in containerization and orchestration of applications.

Cloud-based systems:

• AWS, Azure, or GCP: Experience in working with cloud-based systems

Machine Learning:

• Tensor Flow, Python & Tensor Flow JS, Pytorch: Familiarity with machine learning frameworks and libraries.

Data Visualization:

• Elastic search, Logstash, and Kibana: Experience in log management and data visualization.

Methodologies:

• Agile, Scrum development methodologies

Version Control:

• Git, SVN, and other version control systems

Bachelor in Choreographic Composition with mention in Dance Theatre, Universidad Nacional de las Artes (U.N.A) National University of Arts, Buenos Aires

May 2010 — December 2015

- Professional Choreographer
- Artistic Production